history is the past. It is not
the future. Let's talk about
all of this with Emily Rowland.
She is co-chief investment
strategist at Manulife, John
Hancock Investments. Sorry
about your Red Sox.
>> I know it was tough.
>> It's tough. All right. Emily,
outside of baseball, it's one
historical stat, okay? But I
like it. It's better than it.
Market's usually fall 7.7% is
the direction of this market up.
>> I mean, Brian nothing can
stop this market right now.
It's all about momentum. It's
been about technicals. It's
been about embracing the
pockets of the market that are
up. And we've seen this almost
relentless dip buying take
place. And now we've got
valuations at almost 23 times
forward earnings. So markets
are priced for perfection. In a
not so perfect world.
>> That makes me nervous. What
you just said.
>> Yeah. Well the good news
about it is that the
denominator of the PE ratio is
more important to us. That's
the earnings.
>> That's going.
>> Up earnings in the United
States. The engine is on right
now. And that's really
important because we have the
highest quality companies with
the best earnings revisions
here in the United States. You
think about speculation. Just
go overseas. You look at the
MSCI Eafe. It's up 30% this
year in US dollars on 1%
earnings growth. Chinese stocks
are up almost 40% on 0%
earnings growth. Some of these
European countries have
negative GDP and they're
sporting some of the best.
>> We've talked about it
Slovakia, Slovenia, Poland,
Austria, Germany, Taiwan, Japan,
China Taiwan I said Taiwan
twice. Those are all going up.
>> Yeah. Why it is so I you
know, as a market strategist,
I'm never I never want to say
we don't get it. But in a way,
if you're somebody that focuses
on the macro puzzle, it's hard
to square with the performance.
We've seen this sell America
everything trade since the
height of Liberation Day,
whether it's stocks, whether
it's bonds, whether it's the US
dollar. Of course, the dollar
being down 910% year to date
has been very much accretive to
the performance in some of
these countries. But to us it's
the trend is your friend. And
that's the best friend of a
short term investor.
>> Well, listen, stock market
tends to go up what, 7,277% of
the time. So that's fine. Are
you worried at all, Emily, that
the e the denominator as you
say, is all based on one thing
that AI behemoth. Yeah. That's
all we talk about every day.
And without that I don't know
how much earnings growth there
is.
>> It is a concern. And you
know frankly without AI the
economy wouldn't be doing as
well. And the market clearly
would not be doing as well. But
when I look for, you know, over
time, we're huge believers that
stock prices follow profits.
And when you're looking for
profits right now, you're
finding it in United States
technology companies. But what
you want to think about doing
right now is what we're
drafting the market. So the
equity investors are on a
straightaway right now. They're
in fifth gear, whatever you
want to call it. We are right
behind that lead car. We're
participating, but we're owning
higher quality stocks with
better balance sheets within
the technology sector up in
market cap, staying away from
those more speculative corners
of the market participating,
but being mindful that some
mistakes could be made.
>> Did you bring all the racing
references just for me? All the
car straight away, fifth gear
turns.
>> I did, and I was really
nervous that I was going to get
some of the no.
>> It's great. I listen as a 30
year car racer, I get it. But
here's the thing. I also know
if you're going down that
straightaway, unless you're a
dragster, even dragsters
eventually slow down. Yeah. And
there's stuff that happens to
the race car and there's things
in the road. What is the risk
right now? What do you what do
you guys perceive your John
Hancock Manulife. Right. Your
job is your risk averse, as
they might say. What are what
are the risks to manage through
right now?
>> Well, I think the biggest
risk in markets right now is
that there is no risk. And
that's.
>> What that's.
>> Impossible about today. So
the risk is that there is some
type of froth, a bubble that
gets burst. And it's a key
reason that we're diversifying
within equity exposure. Midcaps
are a favorite area right now.
They have a completely
different sector composition
than their large cap
counterparts, with areas like
industrials and regional banks
that are benefiting right now
from M&A. They're trading at a
30% discount.
>> Why does anybody care?
Nobody loves Jan Brady Peter
Brady right. Like they've got
things to offer too.
>> Well I was about to tell you
that we like income and bonds
too. But definitely nobody
cares about that.
>> But why don't they care.
Those are valuable parts of the
market. There's we've got a
guest on coming up later on in
the show. It's going to talk
about investing in small and
mid-cap companies with his
buyout fund. There are great
companies, amazing companies. I
talked to their CEOs. They're
frustrated. They're like, it
doesn't matter if I grow
earnings 20% a year, Brian,
nobody seems to care.
>> Right.
>> There's that's a problem.
>> It is a problem. But it's
not a problem for investors
that are looking for something
that's on sale. It's really
hard to find anything that's on
sale. I'm a big shopper. I'm
always looking for bargains.
Mid-caps in the United States
are one of the only places
we're finding right now.
Everybody used to come on your
show and say, buy international
stocks because they're cheap.
Guess what? They're not cheap
anymore. Us mid-caps are the
place. Small caps were a little
bit concerned because of some
of the